http://www.lrb.co.uk/privacy

CloseSearchMore search OptionsAdvanced searchSearch by contributorBrowse our cover archiveBrowse by SubjectArts & CultureBiography & MemoirHistory & ClassicsLiterature & CriticismPhilosophy & LawPolitics & EconomicsPsychology & AnthropologyScience & TechnologyCloseCloseAcceptCloseCloseMy Account·Sign outSign inHomeThe PaperLatest IssueArchiveContributorsAbout the LRBSubjectsArts & CultureBiography & MemoirHistory & ClassicsLiterature & CriticismPhilosophy & LawPolitics & EconomicsPsychology & AnthropologyScience & TechnologyBlogPodcasts & VideosEventsShopBookshopCake ShopLRB StoreSubscribeCloseSearchMore search OptionsSearch by contributorBrowse our cover archiveBrowse by SubjectArts & CultureBiography & MemoirHistory & ClassicsLiterature & CriticismPhilosophy & LawPolitics & EconomicsPsychology & AnthropologyScience & Technology
Document History16 August 2002: First public version of this document.15 October 2002: Cookie server names updated.15 June 2004: Scope includes online content of the London Review Bookshop; cookie server names updated.12 December 2007: Acceptance of cookies is required by subscribers wishing to view subscriber-only content.21 October 2009: Revisions to reflect technical developments for new website launch.28 May 2012: Expanded and amended information about our use of cookies.17 July 2013: Updated and expanded cookie information.The London Review of Books (LRB) has created this statement to demonstrate our commitment to your privacy, to explain how we collect information and to explain how we use the information we collect about our web site users.If you have any questions about this privacy statement please address them to registrar@lrb.co.ukScopeThis privacy statement refers to the London Review of Books website, the London Review Bookshop website and the London Review of Books app (iOS and Android) (hereafter collectively referred to as ‘LRB Website and App’), and does not necessarily reflect the use of data gathered on subscribers to the print edition of the London Review of Books or those who have taken advantage of London Review of Books advertising promotions unrelated to the LRB Website and App.This statement is subject to change at any time. The way we use any information will be subject to the privacy statement that is current when that information is gathered. Please check this page regularly to see any changes.How we collect and use informationCookiesCookies are short strings of text sent to your browser and stored by your computer. Most commercial web sites use cookies. We use cookies to remember your preferences and to reference information about the time and extent of your use of the LRB Website and App. We use this information for purposes of system administration and to track potential abuse of our terms and conditions of use. We also use this information in an aggregated form for purposes of marketing and as information to potential advertisers and subscribers. We do not use this information in any way that is personally identifying.We also use cookies for authentication and to remember the logged-in status of registered users and subscribers who use our extended subscriber services.Most browsers have ‘preference’ settings which alert you when cookies are being received and allow you to reject them before they are stored or delete them after they have been stored. If you choose to reject cookies you will still be able to use the LRB Website and App, but functionality may be reduced and subscribers may be unable to use our extended subscriber services or view subscriber-only content.We may remarket your information. Remarketing is a way for us to connect with users, based upon your past interactions with the LRB Website and App. Third-party marketing vendors may be hired by the LRB to perform remarketing services. As a result, third-party vendors, including Google, may show LRB ads on sites on the internet. Third-party vendors, including Google, use cookies to serve ads based on a user’s prior visits to the LRB Website and App.To opt out of customized Google Display Network ads click here. To find out more about how Google uses any data it collects please visit www.google.com/privacy_ads.html.Any information collected is used only for remarketing purposes and will not be used by them for any other purpose.IP addressYour IP address is a numeric code which is assigned to your computer every time you connect to the internet. Typically for home users it will not identify your computer exactly but will identify the service provider via whom you connect to the internet. We use aggregated IP address information to compile reports on the demographics of the usage of the LRB Website and App for purposes of system adminstration, marketing, as information to potential advertisers and subscribers, and to track potential abuse of our terms and conditions of use. We do not use IP address information in a form that is personally identifiable except where the users of that IP address have been responsible for violation of our terms and conditions of use.Subscriptions, sales and other servicesWhen you use the LRB Website and App to subscribe to the London Review of Books magazine or for a web subscription, to purchase goods and services, or to update your subscription data, we will need you to provide certain information which enables you to be identified as an individual (name, address, e-mail, credit card details, and so on). This information is necessary for us to process your order or update your details.To enable us to improve our products and services for your benefit we may, providing we have your permission, contact you to ask if you wish to participate in our customer research programme. This may include an invite to join website usability testing which helps us to find ways to improve our website. You will always have the option to ignore the request or to decline.Your email address will be added to the London Review of Books email alert service, so that you can stay informed about new issues, events and offers. You may unsubscribe at any time by following the link at the bottom of each email.We would also like to keep you informed by post and telephone about our products and services.We may associate information referenced by cookies with personal information which you provide to us online. We will not disclose your personal information to third parties except in the following cases:(1) When it is necessary to provide you with a service you have requested.(2) Under circumstances required by law: when we believe in good faith that a law or legal process requires it or where we believe disclosure is necessary to protect or enforce our rights, the rights of our contributors whose copyright material is under our control, or the rights of other users of the LRB Website and App whose personal information is under our control.Newsletters, online forums and linksNewsletter and information sign upIf you sign up for any newsletter we might offer on the LRB Website and App we will hold your e-mail address securely in a list. We will make sure that each newsletter carries information about how to opt out of the list and how to remove your name from the list so that you will be able to choose to stop receiving the newsletter at any time if you so wish.Public ForumsIn the future we may make chat rooms, forums, message boards, and/or news groups available to users of the LRB Website and App. Please remember that any information that is disclosed in these areas becomes public information and you should exercise caution when deciding to disclose your personal information. Your participation in any public forum which we provide is subject to the LRB’s terms and conditions of use.Advertisers and commercial associatesThe LRB Website and App contains advertisements and promotional links to web sites operated by third parties. While we would never knowingly link to a site which we believed to be trading in bad faith, the LRB is not responsible for the content of these web sites and we take no responsibility for the content, privacy practices, goods or services offered by these sites. Specific provisions in the LRB Website and App’s terms and conditions of use apply to the content of all advertisements and access to all promotional linked web sites.Contextual linksArticles on the LRB Website and App sometimes contain links to third party web sites. These links, provided by contributors to the LRB, are provided on a contextual basis and are relevant to the essays in which they appear. The London Review of Books is not responsible for the content, business practices or privacy practices of such web sites. Specific provisions in the LRB Website and App’s terms and conditions of use apply to use of these links.SecurityThe LRB Website uses SSL (secure socket layer) encryption for all financial transactions (e.g. subscribing to the LRB using our online service, purchases from the London Review Bookshop). All data we collect about users of the LRB Website is similarly protected.Accepting this privacy statementBy using the LRB Website and App you signify your acceptance of this privacy statement and our terms and conditions of use. If you do not agree, or are not comfortable with any policy in this statement, your only remedy is to not use the LRB Website and App. If you are concerned about any cookies which have already been issued to you by the LRB Website and App, you can delete cookies served to your browser by the servers at "lrb.co.uk", "www.lrb.co.uk", "lrbshop.co.uk" and "www.lrbshop.co.uk".If this privacy statement is not accepted in full, use of the LRB Website and App must be terminated immediately.Download the LRB app
Read anywhere with the London Review of Books app, available now from the App Store for Apple devices, Google Play for Android devices and Amazon for your Kindle Fire.
Read MoreSign up to our newsletter
For highlights from the latest issue, our archive and the blog, as well as news, events and exclusive promotions.
Newsletter Preferences
Please enable Javascript
This site requires the use of Javascript to provide the best possible experience. Please change your browser settings to allow Javascript content to run.
